Americans for Progressive Israel Records TAM.147
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Americans for Progressive Israel Records
1961-1991
TAM.147
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
1.0 linear feet (1 box)
Americans for Progressive Israel-Hashomer Hatzair.
Box 1
Arrangement
Arranged in one alphabetical series
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Americans for Progressive Israel (API) was founded in 1947 to function as a less ideologically-based support organization by the Hashomer Hatzair, a socialist-Zionist organization. API, now Meretz USA, publishes Israel Horizons (1952-present), is active in international Zionist work, and conducts educational programs. This unprocessed collection consists mainly of API's research files on topics of concern.
Scope and Contents note
The collection focuses on events and issues in Israel, notably Israel's relations with the Arab world, and contains correspondnce, minutes, annual reports and other administrative matial. There is also some correspondence and administrative material, including minutes and annual reports.
Americans for Progressive Israel-Hashomer Hatzair.; World Hashomer Hatzair.; Annual reports.; Arab-Israeli conflict |x Foreign public opinion, American.; Correspondence.; Files (document groupings); Israel |x Foreign relations |z Arab countries; Israel |x Politics and government; Jews |z United States |x Attitudes toward Israel.; Labor Zionism |z United States.; Labor Zionists |z United States.; Minutes.; Records (documents); Zionists |z United States.
- 8th Biennial National Conference for Progressive Israel, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Agronoff, Michael A. “Jewish Identity: Dialogue with Jewish Youth” (22 pp.), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Americans for a Safe Israel "Breirah Counsel for Judaism" (23 ppg.), 1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- API Newsletter, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- API Projects in Israel, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Arab Vote, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Arab-Jewish Relations, c. 1950s-1960s (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Background Bulletin, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Civil Rights and Peace Movement, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Commentary 69/1: Liberalism and the Jews, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Conference: The Middle East Between War and Peace, New Outlook (International Symposium, Washington, DC), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Conference: Three Years to Camp David (Tel Aviv), 1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1965-1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence Histadrut, 1973-1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence Mapam, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Efrati, Amiram, Interview with, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1981-1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Flapan, Simha and Jibran Majdelang "Zionism, Racism and the Arabs (A Debate over De-Zionization)," reprint (38 pp.), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Givat Haviva (21 pp.), 1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Haggadah (Pessach), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Hakibbuz Ha'artzi/Hashomer Hatzair, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Israel and Palestine Political Report, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Israel Horizons, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Israel Horizons: Articles, Drafts, Typescripts, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Israel Horizons: Articles, Drafts, Typescripts, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Israel Horizons: Material for "Next Issue" (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Israel Horizons: Poetry, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Jewish Labor Committee Review, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Jewish Liberation Information Service, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Jewish Liberation Journal, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Jewish Liberation Project, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Jewish Radical, The (Journal), 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- La'Inyan (Journal), 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Lebanon, c. 1982 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Majus, Jacob. "Detente" (26 pp.), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Mapam: Direct Line from Israel, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Mapam International Service, 1961-1989 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Mapam; London Office, c. 1964-1985 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Nahumi, Mordechai "Rise and Decline of Arab Guerilla and Terror" (109 pp.), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Religious Zionism, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Religious Socialism, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Sharsheret, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Shefa Quarterly, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Syrkin, Marie; "Jews and Revolutionary Movements" (pamphlet, 27 pp.) (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Tadmit Newsletter, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Zionist Election Affair: API, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 49)